[ people chattering ]
[ woman laughing ]
[ waves breaking ]
( Tom ) What 's your name again ?
( Chrissie ) Chrissie .
Where are we going ?
Swimming .
Slow up . Slow down .
I 'm not drunk ! Slow down !
Wait . I 'm coming .
I 'm coming .
I 'm definitely coming .
Whoa ! Hold on .
[ Tom exclaims ]
( Tom ) I can swim .
[ panting ]
I just can 't walk or undress myself .
[ chuckling ]
[ Chrissie sighing ]
( Chrissie ) Come on in the water !
Take it easy . Take it easy .
[ Chrissie gasping ]
( Chrissie ) Oh , God , help !
Help !
[ Chrissie screaming ]
Please help me !
( Tom ) I 'm coming . I 'm coming .
It hurts !
No !
[ choking ]
[ screaming ]
Oh , my God ! Oh , God !
[ continues screaming ]
( man on radio ) ... local fishing reported good .
Amity Boat Rental Yard 's opening early
to prepare for the annual seasonal rush .
This is WISS ...
[ sighs ]
( Brody ) How come the sun didn 't use to shine in here ?
We bought the house in the fall ,
and this is summer .
Somebody feed the dogs .
Right .
Do you see the kids ?
[ newscaster chattering on radio ]
They must be in the back yard .
In Amity you say " yard . "
Yeah , they 're in the " yard , " not too " far " from the " car . "
How 's that ?
Like you 're from New York .
Mom , I got cut . I got hit by a vampire .
You guys were playing on those swings , weren 't you ?
Those swings are dangerous .
Stay off there . I haven 't fixed them yet .
I think you 're going to live .
It 's not the prettiest thing I 've ever seen .
Hello .
Yes .
Can I go swimming ?
Yeah , but let me clean this thing off first .
What do they usually do ?
Wash up , or float up , or what ?
Oh , no ... no ... no ... no .
Keep them there . Keep them there .
I 'll be out in about , uh ,
15 ... 15 , 20 minutes . All right ?
Dry you off .
Okay .
Okay , go on , get a Band-Aid .
( Brody ) Got to go . Missing person .
Season hasn 't started .
Nobody 's even here yet .
Listen , Chief ,
be careful , will you ?
In this town ?
Hey . Hi , Dad .
Wait a minute . Let me get on .
I want my cup back !
You 'll get it . Okay .
Wave goodbye . Bye .
[ man chattering on radio ]
( Brody ) Nobody saw her go into the water ?
( Tom ) Somebody could 've .
I was sort of passed out .
You mean , she ran out on you ?
No , sir .
She must 've drowned .
Look , I reported it to you , didn 't I ?
You live here ?
No . Hartford .
I go to Trinity . My folks live in Greenwich .
Your folks were born here , right ?
Yeah , I 'm an Islander .
They moved off when my dad retired .
You an Islander ?
No . New York City .
You here for the summer ? Come on .
[ whistle blowing ]
Hold it right there .
[ seagulls cawing ]
( Brody ) Oh , Jesus .
Well , you 're up awful early .
Is the Chief in there ?
Well , Chief , what have you got on ?
Polly , if this new filing system is gonna work ,
you 've got to keep outdated stuff off my desk .
Just the pending , all right ?
Yes , Chief .
Now we got a bunch of calls about that karate school .
It seems that the 9-year-olds from the school have been
[ phone buzzing ] karate-ing the picket fences .
Chief Brody 's office . The medical inspector .
( Brody ) Yeah .
Sir , the Fire Chief wants you to go over the Fourth of July ...
Polly , I want a list of all the water activities
that the city fathers are planning for today , all right ?
( Polly ) By the way ...
Hendricks ! Hey , Chief .
Where do we keep the " Beach Closed " signs ?
We never had any . No ?
There 's a dead truck with New Hampshire plates
in front of my store .
( Brody ) Just have him fill out the form .
Just fill it out .
[ dog barking ]
# # [ drums beating ]
[ birds chirping ]
[ whistle blowing ]
Hey , look what the kids did to my fence .
8 and 9-year-olds ...
Glasses ?
Yeah , glasses .
I 'll call you later in the afternoon . I promise .
[ drums continue beating ]
This stuff ain 't going to help me in August .
The summer ginks come down here in June .
You haven 't got one thing on here I ordered .
Not a beach umbrella , not a sun lounger ,
no beach balls .
If I can 't get service ...
Chief !
Chief , Polly sent me to tell you that
there 's a bunch of Boy Scouts out in Avril Bay
doin ' the mile swim for their merit badges .
I couldn 't call them in , there 's no phones out there .
Okay . Come on , get out of there .
Take this stuff back to the office ,
and get to work on those signs . Right .
" Beaches Closed . No Swimming . By order of the Amity P.D. "
Let Polly do the printing .
What 's the matter with my printing ?
Hey , Chief ! Chief Brody !
( Vaughn ) What have you got there ?
Listen , we had a shark attack
at South Beach this morning , Mayor .
Fatal . I have to batten down the beach .
( scoutmaster ) Okay , Albert , come on , you kook .
Keep your arms up .
[ scoutmaster chattering ]
( Brody ) Charlie , Charlie ,
take me out to those kids , will you ?
[ car horn honking ]
[ scoutmaster shouting ]
[ drawbridge alarm beeping ]
Martin .
Martin , y-you 're gonna shut down
the beaches on your own authority ?
But what other authority do I need ?
Well , technically , you need a civic ordinance
or a resolution by a board of ...
That 's just going by the book .
We 're really a little anxious that
you 're , uh , you 're rushing into something serious here .
This is your first summer , you know .
What does that mean ?
I 'm only trying to say that Amity is a summer town .
We need summer dollars .
If people can 't swim here ,
they 'll be glad to swim at the beaches
of Cape Cod , the Hamptons , Long Island .
That doesn 't mean we have to serve them up a smorgasbord .
But we 've never had that kind of trouble in these waters .
What else could 've done that to that girl ?
A boat propeller ?
Well , I think , uh , possibly , uh , yes , a boating accident .
That 's not what you told me on the phone .
I was wrong .
We 'll have to amend our reports .
And you 'll stand by that ?
I 'll stand by that .
Martin , a ... a summer girl goes swimming ,
swims out a little far .
She tires , fishing boat comes along ...
It 's happened before .
I don 't think you appreciate the gut reaction
people have to these things .
Larry , I appreciate it .
I 'm just reacting to what I was told .
Martin , i-it 's all psychological .
You yell , " Barracuda ! " and everybody says , " Huh , what ? "
You yell , " Shark ! "
we 've got a panic on our hands on the Fourth of July .
( Vaughn ) Okay .
You can take us back now .
( woman ) Mommy . Here 's mommy , here .
I 'm going to get my raft and go back out in the water .
Let me see your fingers .
Alex Kintner , they 're beginning to prune .
Just let me go out a little longer .
Just 10 more minutes .
Thanks .
[ girl exclaiming ]
( Mrs. Taft ) There are no Islanders .
None of them are from the island .
It 's just a big bother .
( Mr. Taft ) They 're bringing in ...
All I want to know ...
I just want to know one simple thing :
When do I get to become an Islander ?
Ellen , never , never .
You 're not born here ,
you 're not an Islander . That 's it .
# # [ music playing ]
[ people chattering ]
[ growling ]
( man on radio ) Nantucket Ferries
to Amity , Martha 's Vineyard and Nantucket islands .
Monday to Thursday , 8 : 40 , 1 : 15 , 5 : 45 and 6 : 00 p.m.
Starting July 1 , 8 : 30 p . M ...
( man ) Terry , come back here !
[ Mr. Taft and Mrs. Taft chattering ]
( Mrs. Taft ) But don 't bother him . Come right back .
( Mr. Taft ) Okay . L ... I won 't .
Hey , Martin , I know you got a lot of problems downtown ,
but I 've got a couple of problems at the house
I wish you 'd take care of .
One , I 've got some cats parking
in front of the house , I can 't get ...
[ girl screaming ]
And that garbage truck next to the office ,
that 's terrible .
So what I need is a red zone .
It 's a simple thing you can take care of .
You 've done it before .
Honey , would you come here a minute , please ?
[ kids chattering ]
Are you okay ?
Yeah , I 'm fine . Fine .
Listen , if the kids going in the water
is worrying you ,
No , no .
... they can ... they can play out here on the beach .
It 's all right . Let them go .
It 's cold .
[ chuckling ]
We know all about you , Chief .
You don 't go in the water at all , do you ?
That 's some bad hat , Harry .
# # [ music playing ]
Chief Brody , you are uptight .
Come on . That 's it .
[ all chattering ]
[ girl shrieking ]
# Oh , do you know the muffin man #
# The muffin man # #
Tippet ! Tippet !
Tippet !
Tippet ! Come on , Tippet !
( boy ) Tippet !
[ children exclaiming ]
Did you see that ?
[ screaming ]
Blood !
[ children screaming ]
Get everybody out !
Everybody out !
Get them out !
[ people screaming ]
Michael , get out of the water !
[ people chattering ]
( man ) Take it easy .
Alex ?
( man ) Alex Kintner is the kid who was missing at the beach .
His mother said it was the ...
We don 't even know if there 's a shark around here .
Oh , look , I can 't argue with you .
I can 't talk to you .
I have to talk to Mrs. Kintner .
Because this is going to turn into a contest .
Look , it 's not just the Gazette .
She 's advertising in out-of-town papers .
I suggest we move back to council
chambers where we 'll have more room .
I 'm responsible for public safety here .
Then go out there tomorrow
and see that no one gets hurt .
It 's a small story .
I 'll bury it as deep as I can .
The ad is gonna run on the back
along with the grocery ads .
Right in here , please .
Move on in , please .
[ all chattering ]
Why do you insist on playing the heavy ?
Look , I have a point of view and I think
it speaks for many of the people here .
[ people chattering ]
Not only me , because I have the motel .
How do you feel about it ?
Can 't help it .
Please , let 's have some order .
[ gavel pounding ]
Let 's have order , please .
Any special questions ?
Uh , is that $ 3,000 bounty on the shark in cash or check ?
[ all laughing ]
I don 't think that 's funny .
I don 't think that 's funny at all , sorry .
All right . All right .
That 's private business
between you fishermen and Mrs. Kintner .
Martin , would you please ...
Chief Brody .
Uh , I just , uh , I just want to tell you
what we 're planning so far .
( Meadows ) What about the beaches , Chief ?
We 're going to put on the summer , the extra summer deputies
as soon as possible .
And then we 're gonna try and use
uh , shark spotters on the beach .
Are you going to close the beaches ?
Yes , we are .
[ all exclaiming ]
We 're also planning to bring in some experts
from the Oceanographic Institute on the mainland .
( Vaughn ) Only 24 hours .
I didn 't agree to that .
Only 24 hours .
( woman ) 24 hours is like three weeks !
[ people chattering ]
[ scraping ]
[ chuckles ]
You all know me . Know how I earn a livin ' .
I 'll catch this bird for you .
It ain 't gonna be easy . Bad fish .
Not like goin down to the pond
and chasing ' bluegills or tommy cods .
This shark , swallow you whole .
Shakin ' , tenderizin ' .
Down you go .
And we got to do it quick .
Got to bring back the tourists
that 'll put all your businesses on a paying ' basis .
But it 's not gonna be pleasant .
I value my neck a lot more than $ 3,000 , Chief .
( Quint ) I 'll find him for $ 3,000 ,
but I 'll catch him and kill him for $ 10,000 .
You got to make up your minds .
Gonna stay alive and ante up ,
gonna play it cheap and be on welfare the whole winter .
I don 't want no volunteers .
I don 't want no mates .
There 's too many captains on this island .
$ 10,000 for me , by myself .
For that , you get the head ,
the tail , the whole damn thing .
Thank you very much , Mr. Quint .
We 'll , uh , we 'll take it under advisement .
Mr. Mayor , Chief ,
ladies and gentlemen .
[ clock ticking ]
[ both exclaiming ]
Oh , God , you scared me .
Oh .
Uh .
You know , Ellen ,
people don 't even know how old sharks are .
I mean , if they live 2,000 , 3,000 years ...
They don 't know .
Enough . Enough .
You 're not gonna even be able to go to sleep tonight here .
Here . Come on .
Thanks .
Oh .
[ sighs ]
Want to get drunk and fool around ?
Oh , yeah .
Hey , Mikey really loves his present .
Where is he ?
Sitting in it .
Good God .
[ children chattering ]
All right , Michael , out of the boat !
Tied up to the jetties , sittin ' in the boat .
I 'm helping Michael .
Get out of that boat !
( Michael ) Hi , Dad .
Just a little longer . Please ?
Martin , it 's his birthday tomorrow .
I don 't want him on the ocean !
He 's not on the ocean , he is in a boat .
He 's not gonna go in the water .
I don 't think he 'll go in the water again ,
after what happened yesterday .
All right , now don 't say that .
I don 't want that to happen , you know that .
( Brody ) I want him to read the boating regulations ,
the rules , you know , before he goes out on his own .
Michael , did you hear your father ?
Out of the water now !
Now !
( Charlie ) I 'm tired .
Let 's stop before someone reports us .
( Denherder ) Don 't worry .
The Chief lives on the other side of the island .
Am I coming in straight ?
Don 't worry about it . Just keep rowing .
[ Charlie grunting ]
# # [ Charlie whistling ]
We better catch somethin ' ,
this is my wife 's holiday roast .
Don 't worry about it .
$ 3,000 buys an awful lot of roast .
[ grunting ]
Come and get it .
( Denherder ) The tide 's taking it right out .
Can 't we go home ?
[ clock ticking ]
# # [ both whistling ]
[ clattering ]
Hey , hey , he 's takin ' it .
He 's takin ' it . He 's takin ' it . Hey !
( Charlie ) Go ! Go ! Go !
Charlie , take my word for it ,
don 't look back ! Swim , Charlie !
Swim , come on , Charlie ! Swim !
Come on ! To me , boy ! Come on !
Come on , Charlie ! Swim ! To me !
Come on , Charlie , keep coming .
Keep swimming .
Come on , a little more . Atta boy .
( Charlie ) I can 't get up . I can 't get up .
Give me your hand , Charlie . Just give me your hand .
( Charlie ) Help me ! Help me !
Get your feet out of the water !
[ Charlie panting ]
( Charlie ) Can we go home now ?
[ car horn honking ]
[ people chattering ]
( Hendricks ) So then Denherder and Charlie
sat there trying to catch their breath ,
and figure out how to tell Charlie 's wife
what happened to her freezer full of meat .
That 's not funny . That 's not funny at all .
Mrs. Kintner must 've put her ad in Field Stream .
Looks more like The National Enquirer .
[ men chattering ]
All right , hold it . Hold it .
Hold everything . I said , hold it !
Hello .
Hello back , young fellow . How are you ?
Say , I hope you 're not goin ' out
with those nuts , are you ?
[ ship horn blowing ]
[ people chattering ]
The Weetock boat 's gotta move out first .
You have to move out or he can 't get out at all .
Don 't raise sail , you 're going to luff it .
You got a paddle on the boat ?
I got a paddle .
Scull it out of here .
Officer , Officer , wait a second ,
wait a second . Just ...
Hey , how many guys are you gonna put aboard that boat ?
( skipper ) Whatever 's safe , right ?
Yeah , well , that ain 't safe .
Hey , hey , watch it , that 's dynamite .
What are you doing with that ?
Where are you going with that ?
I 'm going on the boat .
Oh , no , no , no . Please , please ,
help me get those guys out of the boat , will you ?
Sure . Come on .
Gentlemen , gentlemen ,
the officer asked me to tell you
that you 're overloading that boat !
( Hunter ) Go on , get out of here .
( skipper ) You ain 't going . What do you care ?
Then can you tell me
if there 's a good restaurant or hotel on the island ?
( Hunter ) Yeah , you walk straight ahead .
[ men chuckling ]
They 're all going to die .
Hi , listen to me .
We 've got some road block signs outside .
You ... you gotta get somebody to help us .
Yeah , get some ... Get those road block signs
out on the highway .
Because we 've got more people down here
than we can handle .
What 're you doing out there ?
These are your people . Go and talk to them .
Those aren 't my people .
They 're from all over the place .
You see all the license plates ?
Connecticut , Rhode Island , New Jersey .
I 'm all by myself out there .
What happened to the extra help ...
That 's not until the Fourth of July .
Between now and then , it 's you and me .
Uh , you know those guys in the fan-tail launch out there ?
None of them are getting out of the harbor alive .
That 's what I 'm talkin ' about .
You know their first names . Talk to those clowns .
Everyone 's seems to be having a good time today .
Tell me about it .
Polly , I 'll get back to you .
Listen , could you tell me how I could find Chief Brody ?
Who are you ?
Matt Hooper .
I 'm from the , uh , Oceanographic Institute .
Oh , for Christ 's sakes . You 're the guy we called .
I 'm Brody . I 'm Brody .
Oh , I 'm very glad to meet you .
Glad to meet you , too .
I know you got a lot on your hands .
What can we do for you ?
I think the best thing for me to do is to , uh , see the remains
of the first victim , the girl on the beach .
Okay , fine . Just bear with me , will you ?
Sure .
Wait till we get them silly bastards
down in that rock pile .
There 'll be some fun . They 'll wish
their fathers had never met their mothers
when they start diggin ' the bottoms out ,
and slamming into them rocks , boy .
( fisherman No.1 ) Get away from there , you goddamn fool !
What 's the matter with you ?
You want to swamp us , you crazy son of a bitch ?
( fisherman No.2 ) What are these guys doing out here ?
What the hell are they doin ' back there ?
They 're chumming right now .
Chumming ? What the hell is that ?
They 're tracking the shark .
( fisherman No.3 ) $ 3,000 divided 4 ways is what ?
( fisherman No.4 ) Watch your starboard . Jesus !
Let 's show Mr. Hooper our accident .
" Uh , victim identified as Christine Watkins ,
female Caucasian . "
Yeah , and here 's the way we have it .
Probable boating accident .
Yeah .
Good ?
The height and weight of the victim
can only be estimated from the partial remains .
[ sighing ]
The torso has been severed in mid-thorax .
There are no major organs remaining .
May I have a glass of water , please ?
The right arm has been severed
above the elbow with massive tissue loss
in the upper musculature .
Thank you very much .
Partially denuded bone remaining .
This was no boat accident .
Did you notify the Coast Guard about this ?
No . It was only local jurisdiction .
The left arm , head , the shoulders , sternum ,
and portions of the rib cage are intact .
Do not smoke in here . Thank you very much .
This is what happens .
It indicates the non-frenzy feeding of a large squalus ,
possibly longimanus or isurus glaucus .
Now , the enormous amount of tissue loss
prevents any detailed analysis ,
however , the attacking squalus must be considerably larger
than any normal squalus found in these waters .
Didn 't you get out a boat and check these waters ?
No .
Well , this is not a boat accident .
And it wasn 't any propeller .
It wasn 't any coral reef .
And it wasn 't Jack the Ripper .
[ sighing ]
It was a shark .
[ men clamoring ]
I wanna go AP and UPI .
I want to get on the state wire services .
See if Boston 'll pick it up and go national .
Call Dave Axelrod in New York
and tell him he owes me a favor , all right ?
This is the shot I want with everybody and the fish in it , okay ?
Guys , could we please get organized ?
( Meadows ) I want to get a picture for the paper .
Now , can we just have the ...
Ben Gardner get this ?
( fisherman ) No , no , no , we caught it .
We got it . We got it .
[ men chattering ]
That 's swell .
It 's a beauty , ain 't it ?
( Meadows ) Guys , please , I need a picture for the paper .
Clear out of the way , please .
Just the guys that caught the fish .
Just open it up a little bit , please .
I want to get a picture of the guy with the fish .
Come on , guys . Come on , please .
I need a picture for the paper .
Could we get the sign , please ?
[ people chattering ]
( Meadows ) Kneel down , just like in high school .
One row kneeling , one row standing .
Come on , just get out of the way .
Young fellow , could you step out of the picture ?
Take your rake with you .
( man ) We 're ready .
Thank you .
Can you get that , please .
( photographer ) How 's that ?
Larry .
Larry , you won 't believe it .
What kind of a shark is that ?
I don 't know .
I think it 's a mako .
It 's got a deep throat , Frank .
Yeah , but what kind ? What kind of shark ?
Tiger shark .
A what ?
We can start breathing again .
Is Ben getting plenty of pictures ?
Oh , you bet he is .
What is this bite radius crap ?
That is a big mouth .
You stuff your friggin ' head in there , man ,
and find out if it 's a man-eater , all right ?
[ people chattering ]
All I 'm saying is that it may not be the shark .
It 's just a slight ...
I want you to meet Matt .
This is Larry Vaughn , our mayor .
Matt 's from the Oceanographic Institute .
Nice to meet you .
Terrific , huh , Mayor , huh ?
Martin , there are all kinds of sharks in the waters , you know ?
Hammerheads , white tips , blues , makos .
And the chances that these bozos got the exact shark ...
There are no other sharks like this here .
It 's 100-to-1 . A 100-to-1 .
Now I 'm not saying that this is not the shark .
It probably is , Martin . It probably is .
It 's a man-eater .
It 's extremely rare for these waters .
But the fact is , the bite radius on this animal
is different than the wounds on the victim .
I just ... I wanna be sure . You want to be sure .
We all wanna be sure , okay ?
What I wanna do is very simple .
The digestive system of this animal is very , very slow .
Let 's cut it open .
Whatever it 's eaten in the last 24 hours
is bound to still be in there .
And then we 'll be sure .
It may be the only way to confirm it , huh ?
Look , fellows , let 's be reasonable , huh .
This is not the time or the place
to perform some kind of
a half-assed autopsy on a fish .
And I am not going to stand here
and see that thing cut open
and see that little Kintner boy
spill out all over the dock .
Chief Brody ?
Yes ?
[ sobbing ]
I just found out
that a girl got killed here last week .
And you knew it .
You knew there was a shark out there .
[ continues sobbing ]
You knew it was dangerous .
But you let people go swimming anyway .
You knew all those things ,
but still my boy is dead now .
And there 's nothing you can do about it .
My boy is dead .
I wanted you to know that .
I 'm sorry , Martin . She 's wrong .
No , she 's not .
( Vaughn ) All right , fellows ,
let 's cut this ugly son of a bitch down
before it stinks up the whole island .
Harve , you and Carl take it out tomorrow
and dump it in the drink .
Come here .
Give us a kiss .
Why ?
Because I need it .
[ knocking on door ]
( Ellen ) Get out of here . Hello ?
( Ellen ) Can I help you ?
( Hooper ) The door was open . Mind if I come in ?
Uh , I 'm Matt Hooper .
Oh , Hi . Ellen Brody .
Your husband 's home ?
Yes .
I 'd really , uh , like to talk to him .
Uh , yes , so would I.
Come in . Come in . Can I get you some coffee ?
No , no . No , no , no . Nothing , thank you .
Oh , wine . How nice .
How was your day ?
[ both snickering ]
Swell .
I got , uh , red and white .
I didn 't know what you 'd be serving .
Oh , that 's nice .
Is anyone eating this ?
No .
My husband tells me that you 're in sharks .
[ laughs ]
Excuse me . Well , yes .
l-I 've never heard it quite put that way .
But yes , I am .
I love sharks .
You love sharks ?
Yeah , I love them . I love them .
When I was 12 years old , my father got me
this boat and I went fishing off of Cape Cod .
I hooked a scup and as I was reeling it in ,
I hooked a 4.5 foot baby thresher shark
who proceeded to eat my boat .
He ate my oar , hooks , and my seat cushions .
He turned an inboard into an outboard ,
scared me to death , and I swam back to shore .
When I was on the beach , I turned around
and I actually saw my boat being taken apart .
Ever since then , yes , I have been studying sharks ,
and that 's why I know that I 'm gonna go
to the Institute tomorrow
and tell them that you still have
a shark problem here .
Why do you have to tell them that ? Sorry .
I 'm sorry , I thought that ...
You told me the shark was caught .
I ... I heard it on the news .
I heard it on the Cape station .
They caught a shark , not the shark .
Not the shark that killed Chrissie Watkins .
And probably not the shark that killed the little boy .
Which I wanted to prove today by cutting the shark open ...
You may want to let that breathe ...
Nothing , nothing .
[ laughs ]
Yeah , yeah .
You know , uh , you 're gonna be the only rational man
left on this island after I leave tomorrow .
Where are you going ?
I am going on the Aurora .
The Aurora ? What is that ?
It 's a floating asylum for shark addicts .
It 's pure research , 18 months at sea .
Martin hates boats . Martin hates water .
Martin sits in his car
when we go on the ferry to the mainland .
I guess it 's a childhood thing . It 's , uh ...
There 's a clinical name for it , isn 't there ?
Drowning .
Listen , is it true that most people get attacked
by sharks in three feet of water ,
about 10 feet from the beach ?
Yeah .
And that ... And that before people started to swim
for recreation ...
I ... I mean , before sharks knew what they were missing
that a lot of these attacks weren 't reported ?
That 's right .
Now this shark that ... that swims alone ,
what 's it called ? Rogue . Rogue .
Rogue , yeah .
Now , this guy , he , he , keeps swimming around
in a place where the feeding is good
until the food supply is gone , right ?
That 's called territoriality .
It 's just a theory that I happen to agree with .
Then why don 't we have one more drink ,
and go down and cut that shark open ?
Martin ? Can you do that ?
I can do anything . I 'm the Chief of Police .
[ foghorn blowing ]
We start in the alimentary canal ,
and open the digestive tract .
[ grunts ]
[ panting ]
[ coughing ]
[ exclaims ]
Just like I thought .
What ?
Came up in the Gulf Stream , from southern waters .
He didn 't eat a car , did he ?
No .
Tiger shark 's like a garbage can .
It 'll eat anything .
Somebody probably threw that in the river .
[ panting ]
[ exhales ]
That 's it .
I 've got to close the beach , call the Mayor .
[ panting ]
You got a bigger problem than that , Martin .
You still got a hell of a fish out there
with a mouth about this big .
How do we confirm that by morning ?
If he is a rogue ,
and there 's any truth to territoriality at all ,
we got a good chance of spotting him
between Cape Scott and South Beach .
Where are you going ?
To find him . He 's a night feeder .
On the water ?
We 're not gonna find him on the land .
I 'm not drunk enough to go on a boat .
Yes , you are .
No , I 'm not . Yes , you are .
I can 't do that . Yes , you can .
[ boat engine whirring ]
I 'm telling you , the crime rate
in New York will kill you .
There 's so many problems ,
you never feel like you 're accomplishing anything .
Violence , rip-offs , muggings .
The kids can 't leave the house .
You 've gotta walk them to school .
But in Amity , one man can make a difference .
In 25 years , there 's never been
a shooting or a murder in this town .
No kidding ? Want a pretzel ?
Where are we ?
We 're right in the stretch where he 's been feeding .
Can you get The Late Show on this thing ?
No , it 's a closed circuit TV system .
I have underwater cameras fore-and-aft .
Who pays for all this stuff ?
The government ? The Institute ?
This stuff costs a lot of money .
Well , I , uh , I paid for this mostly myself , actually .
You 're kidding .
No .
You rich ?
Yeah .
Yeah , how much ?
Well , personally , or the whole family ?
Doesn 't make any sense .
I mean , they pay a guy like you to watch sharks ?
Well , uh , it doesn 't make sense for a guy
who hates the water to live on an island either .
It 's only an island if you look at it
from the water .
That makes a lot of sense .
[ electronic buzzing ]
( Brody ) What is that thing doing ?
Well , it 's a , it 's a fish finder .
It 's probably just a school of mackerel or something ,
all clumped together .
[ rapid electronic buzzing ]
Wait a minute .
There 's something else out there .
What is it ?
About 100 yards , south-southwest .
( Brody ) That 's Ben Gardner 's boat .
( Hooper ) You know him ?
It 's all banged up . Sure I know him . He 's a fisherman .
What happened ?
Look , Martin , I gotta go down and check their hull .
Wait . Why don 't we just tow it all in ?
We will , we will . I just got to check something out .
Hit the lights for me .
Let 's tow it in .
Don 't worry , Martin .
Nothing 's gonna happen .
[ panting ]
What am I supposed to do while you 're gone ?
Nothing . Absolutely nothing .
Don 't touch any of the equipment .
I 'll be back in two minutes .
[ gasping ]
[ panting ]
This is a great white , Larry . A big one .
Any shark expert will tell you it 's a killer , a man-eater .
Look , the situation is that apparently a great white shark
has staked a claim in the waters off Amity Island .
He 'll continue to feed here
as long as there 's food in the water .
There 's no limit to what he 'll do .
We 've already had three incidents .
Two people killed within a week .
It 'll happen again .
It happened before . The Jersey beach , 1916 .
Five people were killed ...
In one week .
Tell him about the swimmers .
A shark is attracted to the exact kind of
splashing and activity
that occurs whenever human beings swim .
You cannot avoid it .
Opening the beaches on the Fourth of July is like
ringing the dinner bell .
Look , Mr. Vaughn , Mr. Vaughn ,
I pulled a tooth the size of a shot glass
out of the wrecked hull of a boat out there .
It was the tooth of a great white .
It was Ben Gardner 's boat , all chewed up .
I helped tow it in . You should 've seen it !
Where ... where is that tooth ? Did you see it , Brody ?
No , I didn 't see it . He dropped it on the way in .
I had an accident .
And what did you say the name of this shark is ?
It 's a Carcharodon carcharias .
It 's a great white .
But you ... you don 't have the tooth ?
Look , we depend on the summer people here for our very lives ...
You won 't have a summer
unless you deal with this problem !
We have to close the beach
and hire someone to kill the shark !
I mean , we have to tell the Coast Guard .
You 'll have to contact the Shark Research Panel .
You 'll have to ring this entire harbor !
I don 't think either one of you
are familiar with our problems !
Uh , I think that I am familiar with the fact
that you 'll ignore this particular problem
until it swims up and bites you in the ass !
Wait a second ! Wait a second !
There are two ways to deal with this problem !
You either kill this animal or cut off its food supply .
( Brody ) Larry , we have to close the beaches .
Brody ?
Sick vandalism .
That is a deliberate mutilation
of a public service message .
Now , I want those little paint-happy bastards
caught and hung up by their Buster Browns .
That 's it . I won 't waste my time arguing with
a man who 's lining up to be a hot lunch .
I 'm gonna see you later , Brody .
Please , don 't do this . He 's not ...
[ people chattering ]
Mr. Vaughn ,
What we are dealing with here
is a perfect engine , uh , an eating machine .
It 's really a miracle of evolution .
All this machine does is swim and eat
and make little sharks . And that 's all .
Why don 't you take a long , close look at this sign ?
Those proportions are correct .
You 'd love to prove that , wouldn 't you ?
Get your name into the National Geographic .
[ laughing ]
( Brody ) Larry , Larry , if we make an effort today ,
we might be able to save August .
August ? For Christ 's sake ,
tomorrow 's the Fourth of July !
We will be open for business .
It 's gonna be one of the best summers we 've ever had .
If you are concerned about the beaches ,
do whatever you have to , to make them safe .
But those beaches will be open for this weekend .
[ ship horn blowing ]
[ people chattering ]
I want to know how many men you 're going to send me .
There is no need for me to come to Brisbane
when I have a great white shark right here !
( Brody ) We need men to patrol the swimming area .
We 've gotta have help .
Anybody with a gun or a boat .
[ all chattering ]
Monday !
Is Chief Federal Officer Feldman there ?
Dad . What ?
He 's the little guy with a crew cut .
[ whistles ]
[ horn blowing ]
Operator , isn 't there a phone on the island ?
Could you connect me , please ?
( kid ) Come on , get him ! Get him , come on !
( Brody ) Careful on the beach .
Brody to Gotcha , do you read me ?
The guys from the TV station on the mainland are here .
Oh , all right . I 'll get to them later .
Brody to Scutbucket , please come in .
[ all chattering ]
Okay .
Brody to Daisy , do you read me ?
( Brody ) Fascinating Rhythm , do you read me ?
Come in , Hooper . What do you see ?
Nothing here , Martin . And nothing on sonar .
Amity Island has long been known
for its clean air , clear water ,
and beautiful white-sand beaches .
But in recent days ,
a cloud has appeared on the horizon
of this beautiful resort community .
A cloud in the shape of a killer shark .
( sportscaster on radio ) ... this stadium does hold the water well .
That is very shocking in the outfield .
Two balls , one strike , runners at first and third ...
Fly ball , deep left field .
Jerry Christian goes back , running back near the wall
and he takes it for the out .
Oh , hi , Larry .
Why aren 't you in the water ?
Uh , well , uh ,
I just put some suntan lotion on ,
and , uh , I 'm trying to absorb some ...
Nobody 's going in .
Please , get in the water .
[ radio chattering ]
Yay !
[ helicopter whirring ]
Mike , come here .
Listen , Mike . Do me a favor , will you ?
You and the other guys take the boat
and put it in the pond instead ?
The pond is for old ladies .
I know it 's for the old ladies ,
but just do it for the old man , huh ?
Please ?
All right .
Thanks .
[ whispering ] I 've got Sean .
Michael ! Wait !
Michael , I don 't like you no more .
[ all chattering ]
I can stand Harry , you know ...
Daisy , Daisy , this is Hendricks .
Anything ? Thought I saw a shadow . Over .
( Daisy ) Hendricks , this is Daisy here .
I don 't see anything .
False alarm . Must be this glare .
I 'm pleased and happy to repeat the news
that we have in fact caught and killed
a large predator
that supposedly injured some bathers .
As you see , it 's a beautiful day .
The beaches are open ,
and people are having a wonderful time .
" Amity , " as you know , means " friendship . "
[ both giggling ]
My God !
Jesus Christ ! Fin ! Shark ! 350 !
( guard ) Get in there as fast as you can !
Red one . Red one .
( Hooper ) Martin , get them the hell out of the water .
[ whistles ]
No whistles ! No whistles !
Everybody , please , get out of the water .
Everybody out of the water .
Don 't push !
Everybody out of the water , please .
[ guard chattering on radio ]
[ screaming ]
[ people clamoring ]
( woman ) Come on , guys !
Everybody out of the water !
( Brody ) I want them out of there , guys .
Give an answer , please .
What 's going on out there ?
He made me do it . He talked me into it .
( Brody ) Please , please , move back . Let 's move back .
Let 's give these people some air .
Please , move back . Move back .
Martin , it 's just a hoax .
There are two kids with a cardboard fin .
Is everyone there okay ?
Everyone get out of the water all right ?
( guard ) Folks , we had some practical joker
down there with a fake fin ...
Shark ! A shark !
( girl ) It 's going into the pond ! Shark in estuary !
Now what ?
Michael 's in the pond .
( girl ) It 's going in the pond !
Somebody do something ! It 's in the pond !
Hurry up , get that done .
I can 't do a damn thing .
Get that rope undone .
You gotta untangle that up there .
I 'm doing it !
Hey , fellows , fellows , haul in your sheet .
Make it fast .
[ people screaming ]
You guys , you guys okay over there ?
In the pond !
[ panting ]
[ screaming ]
[ all exclaiming ]
( man ) Somebody get a gun , get a gun shoot it !
Doesn 't anybody have a gun ?
[ crowd screaming ]
Michael !
Is he dead ?
No , he 's not . He 's in shock .
[ Ellen crying ]
( Ellen ) Michael !
[ crying ]
Doctor said he 's okay . Mild shock .
He can go home in the morning .
Thank you . Thank you .
( announcer on PA system ) Dr. Young ...
Hey , how 's my big kid ?
I 'm all right .
You gonna miss me tonight ?
You can watch television .
Want me to bring anything from home ?
My cars . Your cars .
What about ice cream ?
Coffee . Coffee .
[ man chattering on PA system ]
Want to take him home ?
Like to New York ?
No . Home , here .
( announcer on PA system ) Dr. Kevin ...
It 's all my fault .
I 'm sorry , I 'm truly sorry .
You got a pen , Larry ?
Yeah , a pen , you know .
'Cause you 're going to do what you do best .
You 're going to sign this voucher
so I can hire a contractor .
I ... I don 't know if I can do that without ...
I 'm gonna hire Quint to kill the shark .
August ? What ?
August . What ?
What are you talkin ' about ?
Larry , summer 's over .
You 're the mayor of Shark City .
People think you want the beaches open .
I was ... I was ... I was acting
in the ... in the town 's best interest .
You were acting in the town 's best interest .
That 's why you 'll do the right thing .
That 's why you 're going to sign this ,
and we 'll pay that guy what he wants .
Martin .
My kids were on that beach , too .
Sign it , Larry .
[ panting ]
( Quint ) $ 10,000 .
$ 200 a day , whether I catch him or not .
( Brody ) You 've got it .
Get the Mayor off my back
so I don 't have more of this zoning crap .
You 've got that .
One case of apricot brandy , and you buy the lunch .
Two cases .
( Brody ) And you get dinner when you get back .
( Quint ) Champagne , pâte de foie gras ,
Iranian caviar , and don 't forget the color TV .
Chief , you try this . Made it myself .
Pretty good stuff .
Thanks .
Here 's to swimming with bow-legged women .
Excuse me , Chief .
[ water boiling ]
Can 't get a good man these days , under 60 .
All gone at least 35 years .
Don 't drink that .
Mr. Quint .
Mr. Quint ,
you 're gonna need an extra hand .
This is Matt Hooper .
I know him .
I 've crewed three Trans Pacs . Transplants ?
No , he 's from the Oceanographic Institute .
And an America 's Cup trial .
Mr. Hooper , I 'm not talkin ' about
pleasure boating or day-sailing .
I 'm talkin ' about working for a living .
I 'm talkin ' about sharking ' .
Well , I 'm not talkin about hookin
some poor dogfish or sand shark .
I 'm talkin ' about finding a great white .
Porkers ? Talkin ' about porkers , Mr. Hooper ?
Just tie me a sheepshank .
[ exhales ]
I haven 't had to pass basic seamanship in a long time .
You didn 't say how short you wanted it .
How 's that ?
Give me your hands .
Dogfish ?
You got a $ 5,000 net
and you got $ 2,000 worth of fish in it .
Along comes Mr. Whitey ,
and when he 's finished with that net ,
it looks like a kiddies ' scissors class
has cut it up for a paper doll .
You got city hands , Mr. Hooper .
You been countin money all your life .
All right . Hey , I ... I don 't need this .
I don 't need this working-class-hero crap .
You-you 're not going to do this aboard
the ship are you , Mr. Quint ?
Maybe I should go alone .
It 's my party . It 's my charter .
Yeah , it 's your charter , it 's your party .
It 's my vessel .
You 're on board my vessel , I 'm mate , master , pilot ,
and I 'm captain .
[ ship horn blowing ]
I 'll take him for ballast , Chief .
You got him .
( Quint ) Straight-jet , killing lance .
Tail rope , eye splice , M-1 , handy billy , pliers , irons ...
( Hooper ) Sample bottles , dye marker , flares , safety float ,
temperature gauge , spear guns , SMG ...
What are you ?
Some kind of half-assed astronaut ?
[ laughs ]
[ Quint guffawing ]
( Quint ) Take that stuff down below
and you lash it secure , all right ?
[ rattling ]
Jesus H. Christ !
When I was a boy , every little squirt
wanted to be a harpooner or a swordfisherman .
What have you got here ?
A portable shower or a monkey cage ?
An anti-shark cage .
Anti-shark cage ?
You go inside the cage ?
Cage goes in the water ?
You go in the water ? Shark 's in the water .
Our shark .
# Farewell and adieu to you fair Spanish ladies #
# Farewell and adieu , you ladies of Spain #
# For we 've received orders for to sail back to Boston #
# And so nevermore shall we see you again # #
[ Quint laughing ]
Did you take your Dramamine ?
Yes .
I put an extra pair of glasses in your black socks
and ... and there 's the stuff for your nose ,
the zinc oxide and Blistex is in the kit .
( Quint ) Son of a bitch !
Goddamn women today , they can 't handle nothin ' .
Young girls just ain 't quite smart
like their grandmothers were .
That 's got to be Quint .
Colorful , isn 't he ?
He scares me .
[ Quint chattering ]
Don 't use the fireplace in the den ...
What am I gonna tell the kids ?
( Quint ) Go to hell !
Tell ' em I 'm going fishing .
( Quint ) Break it up , will you , Chief ?
Daylight 's wasting ' !
[ boat engine starting ]
Front : bow . Back : stern .
Better get it right , squirt , or I throw your ass
out the little round window on the side !
Come on , Chief .
This isn 't no Boy Scout picnic .
See you got your rubbers .
[ Quint laughing ]
" Here lies the body of Mary Lee
" Died at the age of 103
" For 15 years she kept her virginity
Not a bad record for this vicinity "
All right , Commissioner , fasten your safety belt !
[ Quint chuckling ]
If you see a shark , Hooper , swallow !
[ Quint laughs ]
( Quint ) Up periscope . Rig for depth charge .
Stand by fire drill .
Damage control report .
Nor 'easter comin ' , bad news for Madison Avenue .
I 'm tired of that .
How 's the missus , Chief ?
If they don 't like you going out ,
they 'll love you coming in .
[ Quint snickering ]
# # [ Quint singing ]
Keep that chum line going , Chief .
We got five good miles on it .
Who 's driving this boat ?
Nobody . The tide .
One time , I caught a 16-footer off Montauk .
Had to stick two barrels in him .
Two to wear him down and bring him up .
Nowadays , these kids , they take out everything .
Radar , sonar , electric toothbrushes .
Jesus H. Christ .
Chief , best drop another chum marker .
( Hooper ) Damn it , Martin !
This is compressed air .
What the hell kind of a knot was that ?
You pulled the wrong one !
You screw around with these tanks ,
and they 're gonna blow up .
Yeah , that 's real fine , expensive gear
you 've brought out here , Mr. Hooper .
I don 't know what that bastard shark 's gonna do with it .
Might eat it , I suppose .
Seen one eat a rocking chair one time .
Hey , Chiefie ,
next time , you just ask me which line to pull , right ?
( Quint ) Little brown eel comes out of the cave ,
swims into the hole ,
comes out of the hole ,
goes back into the cave again .
It 's not too good , is it , Chief ?
Well , nothing 's easy , is it ? One more time .
( Brody ) Little brown eel ...
[ clicking ]
[ Brody chattering ]
Hey !
I got it !
What ?
Get behind me .
[ reel whirring ]
( Quint ) Hooper , reverse her !
Taking a hell of a lot of line !
[ engine starting ] Chief , get the scoop out of the bucket !
Wet the reel !
Hooper , reverse her !
Duck your head down , Chief .
We 're swingin ' . Get behind me again .
No more water .
I don 't want you to drown me .
Hooper , you idiot , starboard !
Ain 't you watchin ' it !
Hooper , neutral .
Where 'd he go now ?
He ain 't fooling me .
What 's he yankin ' on now ?
Go on , try it .
I don 't know , Chief ,
I don 't know if he 's very smart or very dumb .
[ grunts ]
Jesus ...
He 's gone under .
He 's gone under the boat .
I think he 's gone under the boat .
Yeah , it 's too easy .
He is a smart , big fish .
He 's gone under the boat .
( Quint ) Keep her steady , now .
I got something very big !
I don 't think so .
Chief ,
Chief , put your gloves on .
You put your gloves on , both of you !
( Quint ) Getting ready to run out again .
Hey , Quint , let it go .
Hey , Hooper , maybe you 're a big yahoo in the lab ,
but out here you 're just supercargo !
If you don 't want to backstroke home , you get down here !
You don 't want to listen to me , don 't listen to me .
It 's not a shark .
The wire 's showing . The wire 's showing .
( Quint ) Unbuckle me .
Get the other side .
It 's a tuna or swordfish
wasting our time .
Take this rod .
Hooper , give the Chief a hand , will you ?
Right !
Oh , shit !
It may be a marlin or a stingray ,
but it 's definitely a game fish .
[ Hooper grunts ]
[ metallic clanking ]
Gaming fish , eh ?
Marlin , stingray bit through this piano wire ?
Don 't you tell me my business again .
You get back on the bridge .
Quint , that doesn 't prove a damn thing .
It proves one thing , Mr. Hooper :
You wealthy college boys don 't have the education enough
to admit if you 're wrong .
What 's the point ? Hooks and lines ?
You lose one , you rig one .
[ engine revving ]
Hooper !
12 minutes , south-southeast , now !
Full throttle !
Aye-aye , sir ! Aye !
You see , what I do , Chief ,
is I trick ' em to the surface .
And then I jab at ' em .
I 'm not gonna haul ' em up like a lot of catfish .
Hooper , full throttle !
I don 't have to take this abuse much longer .
Your head 's bleedin ' .
First aid there .
Brody !
Start that chum line again , will you ?
Let Hooper take a turn .
Hooper drives the boat , Chief .
Stop playing with yourself , Hooper .
Slow ahead , if you please .
You heard him . Slow ahead .
Slow ahead .
I can go slow ahead .
Come on down and chum some of this shit .
You 're gonna need a bigger boat .
Shut off that engine .
That 's a 20-footer .
25 .
Three tons of him .
We 're going to need a bigger boat , right ?
Gotta get to work .
How do we handle this ? How do we handle this ?
Come up front , Martin . I need you .
( Hooper ) He 's circling the boat .
( officer ) This is Amity Point Light Station to Orca .
Come in , Orca .
Orca . Come in .
I have Mrs. Martin Brody here .
Put her on .
( Hooper ) Come on , Martin ! Move ! Move ! Move !
( Brody ) I 'm not going out there !
Beyond the edge of the barrels .
Go to the end of the barrels , further out .
Further out !
Why ?
Go further out ! What for ?
Will you go to the end of the pulpit ?
What ?
I need something in the foreground to give it some scale !
Foreground my ass !
Your husband 's all right . He 's fishing .
He just caught some stripers .
We 'll bring them for dinner .
We ain 't seen anything yet . Over . Out .
I 'm not staying here !
I 'm begging you !
God damn it ! Come here , come here darling .
( Hooper ) Beautiful !
Chief , I want you up on the bridge ,
just take her forward , steady .
I 've never steered a boat in my life .
Just watch my hand , take her steady .
Mr. Hooper , attach the end of this line
to the first keg .
I 've got to get a good shot at that porker 's head .
[ boat engine revving ]
He-he 's coming .
Hooper ? Get clear of the bow .
Hooper !
( Quint ) Hurry up , will you ?
Your turn , Quint .
Hooper , where are you ?
Hooper .
Hurry it up now , tie it on .
He 's coming straight for us .
Don 't screw it up now .
Don 't wait for me .
Come on , Hooper , hurry it up ! Tie it on !
Now .
Kill it ! Kill it !
Now !
Shoot !
Time .
( Quint ) What were you doing ? You knew I had
to get a clean shot right in the head .
All right , let 's see how long
that barrel takes to bring him up .
Bring another barrel !
I 'm coming around again !
What ... what do we do now ? We 're quitting ' , right ?
( Quint ) We got one barrel on him .
So , we stay out here until we find him again .
We could radio in and get a bigger boat ...
# # [ Quint whistling ]
Chief ,
don 't you worry about it , Chief .
It won 't be permanent .
You want to see something permanent ?
Boom !
Hey , Hoop ,
[ laughing ] you want to feel something permanent ?
Just put your hand underneath my cap .
You feel that little lump ?
Knocko Nolans , St. Patty 's Day , Boston .
I got that beat .
It 's a moray eel .
It bit right through my wet suit .
Well , Hoop , now , listen ,
I don 't know about that ,
but I entered an arm-wrestlin ' contest
in a bar in San Francisco . See this ?
I can 't extend that . You know why ?
'Cause in the semi-final
celebrating my third wife 's demise ,
big Chinese fellow , he pulled me right over .
Look at that .
That 's a bull shark .
He scraped me when I was taking samples .
I got somethin ' for you .
There 's a thresher .
You see that ? A thresher 's tail .
Thresher ?
It 's a shark .
You want a drink ? Drink to your leg ?
I 'll drink to your leg .
Okay , so we drink to our legs .
[ snickering ]
I got the crème de la crème .
Right here . Hold on .
Here , you see that ?
You 're wearing a sweater .
Right there . Mary Ellen Moffit .
She broke my heart .
[ snickering ]
What 's that one ?
( Quint ) What ?
That one , there . On your arm .
Oh , well ,
It 's a tattoo . I got that removed .
Don 't tell me . Don 't tell me .
" Mother . "
[ continues snickering ]
What is it ?
Mr. Hooper , that 's the U.S.S. Indianapolis .
You were on the Indianapolis ?
What happened ?
Japanese submarine slammed
two torpedoes into her side , Chief .
I was coming back
from the island of Tinian to Leyte ,
just delivered the bomb , the Hiroshima bomb .
1,100 men went into the water .
Vessel went down in 12 minutes .
Didn 't see the first shark for about half an hour .
Tiger , 13-footer .
You know how you know that
when you 're in the water , Chief ?
You tell by looking from the dorsal to the tail .
Well , we didn 't know .
Because our bomb mission had been so secret ,
no distress signal had been sent .
[ Quint laughs ]
They didn 't even list us overdue for a week .
Very first light , Chief , sharks come cruisin ' ,
so we formed ourselves into tight groups .
You know , kind of like old squares
in a battle like you see on a calendar ,
like the Battle of Waterloo .
The idea was the shark comes to the nearest man
and he starts pounding , hollering and screaming .
Sometimes the shark would go away ,
but sometimes he wouldn 't go away .
Sometimes that shark ,
he looks right into you , right into your eyes .
You know , a thing about a shark ,
he 's got lifeless eyes .
Black eyes , like a doll 's eyes .
When he comes at you , he doesn 't seem to be livin
until he bites you .
Those black eyes roll over white and then ...
Oh , then you hear that terrible high-pitched screamin ' .
The ocean turns red .
In spite of the poundin' and the hollerin ' ,
they all come in .
They rip you to pieces .
You know , by the end of that first dawn ,
we lost 100 men .
I don 't know how many sharks . Maybe 1,000 .
I don 't know how many men , they averaged six an hour .
On Thursday morning , Chief ,
I bumped into a friend of mine ,
Herbie Robinson , from Cleveland .
Baseball player , bosun 's mate .
I thought he was asleep .
Reached over to wake him up .
He bobbed up and down in the water
just like a kind of top .
Upended .
Well ...
he 'd been bitten in half , below the waist .
Noon the fifth day , Mr. Hooper ,
a Lockheed Ventura saw us .
He swung in low and he saw us .
He was a young pilot .
A lot younger than Mr. Hooper .
Anyway , he saw us and he came in low ,
and three hours later ,
a big fat PBY comes down and starts to pick us up .
That was the time I was most frightened .
Waitin ' for my turn .
I 'll never put on a life jacket again .
So , 1,100 men went into the water ,
316 men come out .
The sharks took the rest , June 29 , 1945 .
Anyway , we delivered the bomb .
[ whale crying ]
What 's that ?
It 's a whale .
# Farewell and adieu to you fair Spanish ladies #
# Farewell and adieu , you ladies of Spain #
# Show me the way to go home #
# I 'm tired and I wanna to go to bed #
( both ) # I had a little drink about an hour ago #
# And it 's gone right to my head #
# Wherever I may roam #
# By land , or sea or foam #
# You will always hear me singing this song #
[ sensor beeping ]
# Show me the way to go home #
# Boom , boom , boom #
( all ) # Show me the way to go home #
# I 'm tired and I want to go to bed #
# I had a little drink about an hour ago #
# And it 's gone right to my head #
[ pounding ] # Wherever I may roam #
# On land or sea or foam #
# You can always hear me singing # #
Start the engines .
[ pounding continues ]
( Quint ) Fire her up ! Right in the middle !
He 's busting the shaft .
Chief , put out the fire , will you ?
Pump her out .
Done .
( Quint ) Everybody on deck .
( Hooper ) He ate the light .
( Brody ) Terrific .
Excuse me .
( Hooper ) Quint , what are you doing ?
Don 't waste your time .
Quint , come on .
( Quint ) What 's wrong with this ?
[ gun firing ]
Hooper , take the wheel .
Brody , follow that . Watch for him .
[ gun firing ]
( Hooper ) You okay ?
Hey , Martin ,
You okay ?
# # [ Quint singing ]
[ birds chirping ]
( Quint ) Hey , Chief , more left rudder !
Pull your left hand down .
I can 't . It 'll only go about three inches .
( Hooper ) All of our injectors got scored
from the salt water in the fuel .
Yeah , the housing 's bent , you can hear it .
Try the left rudder again , will you ? More left .
Good . Once again now .
( Brody ) Quint , Quint ,
Quint , Quint , there it is .
What do you say , Chief ?
The barrel is up , it 's right in the stern .
I think he 's right under the keg .
Grab the boat hook .
Quint , if we can get close enough ...
I 've got things on board that 'll kill it .
Just wanna goose him up . Come on .
Okay .
When he runs , you drop that rope
or you 'll lose your hands .
I 've seen fingers torn out at the knuckles .
Whole sea 's bones , full of them .
Hey , boy , give it to me a minute .
Haul in that line or it 'll foul us .
Start the engine .
Where are you going ?
I 'm gonna make a phone call .
Hello , hello .
Hello , mayday , Orca . Coast Guard ?
Coast Guard , this is the Orca .
Do you read me ?
Coast Guard , this is the Orca . Do you ...
Excuse me , Chief .
That 's great ! That 's just great !
Now , where the hell are we , huh ?
[ panting ]
You 're certifiable , Quint , you know that ?
You 're certifiable !
You 're certifiable , but I 'll tell you this !
( Hooper ) Boys ...
Oh , boys ,
I think he 's come back for his noon feeding .
Hook me up another barrel .
Bring her around after him .
( Quint ) Full throttle !
Get me right up alongside of him !
I can 't rev it up that high , it 's not gonna take it !
Five degrees port .
All right , hold your course .
Five degrees port now .
Hold your course .
Fast fish .
( Quint ) Watch my hand .
Be sure you watch my hand ! Follow me . Follow me .
Lad , you watch him now ! Starboard ! Starboard !
Run him down , Hooper .
( Quint ) Run him down ! Run him down !
Hard aport .
Watch him . Starboard .
Starboard !
[ gun firing ]
( Brody ) I can 't believe it .
Two barrels and he 's going down again .
It 's incredible .
They 're up again !
Now what ?
Why don 't we start leading the shark into shore
instead of him leading us out to sea ?
[ boat revving ]
Grab a couple of poles .
Hang on now , we 're going around .
( Quint ) Into starboard . Easy .
I 'm gonna back her off now .
Watch those barrels , boys . Watch ' em .
All right , gentlemen , snag ' em .
Now then , tie them to the stern cleats .
( Quint ) Brody , bring your end around the cleat .
That 's right , it 'll lock itself off .
Give him room , Brody .
[ groaning ]
Stay clear of the line !
( Brody ) Watch it . Stand clear .
Stand away from those stern cleats !
Back home we got a taxidermy man .
He 's gonna have a heart attack
when he sees what I brought him .
Throttle back . You 're losing a cleat .
( Hooper ) My God , this one , too . They 're both going .
He 's eating his way through that line .
He 's working his way right up to us .
Quint ! Come on , Quint . Hurry !
( Hooper ) Quint !
Out of my way .
( Quint ) Watch it .
Untie this . He 'll pull out the transom .
Make it fast ! We got another line in him !
I can 't , it 's tryin ' to run !
( Brody ) We better get another line !
( Quint ) Pull , you son of a bitch !
I hope your back breaks !
Go ahead . Pull your bloody heart out .
Tie him off !
Tie him off .
It 's impossible !
Boys , it 's too tight !
He 's pullin ' us !
We 're breaking up over here !
[ all chattering ]
( Quint ) Get the axe ! Get the axe !
( Hooper ) We 're breaking up ! Cut it ! Cut it !
( Brody ) Watch your hands ! Watch your hands !
( Hooper ) Cut it quick . I can 't hold it !
[ Hooper panting ]
He can 't stay down with three barrels on him .
Not with three barrels , he can 't .
What about us ?
Hooper , get the pump out of the locker
in front of you , will you ?
We 're going to sink , aren 't we ?
( Quint ) Hooper , keep an eye on the barrels .
Pump it out , Chief .
[ boat engine cranking ]
( Hooper ) Starting to go under .
He can 't with three barrels on him .
Not with three he can 't .
You ever have one do this before ?
No .
( Hooper ) He 's chasin ' us . I don 't believe it .
I 'm gonna draw him into the shallows .
Draw him into the shallow water .
I 'm gonna draw him in and drown him .
We 're headin ' in , Brody .
Thank Christ !
You ever had a great white do that ?
No .
[ whistling ]
How far do we have to go ?
Quint , don 't put that much pressure on it .
[ engine thumping ]
Quint , God damn it .
Shut up . Get back there .
[ screaming ]
Hold on .
# Farewell and adieu to you fair Spanish ladies #
# Farewell and adieu , you ladies of Spain #
# For we received order for to sail back to Boston # #
( Hooper ) You idiot , you burned out the bearings .
( Brody ) All right , stop the boat . Stop the boat ! Stop it !
[ engine exploding ]
[ panting ]
Hooper .
Chief .
[ boat creaking ]
Hooper ,
what exactly can you do with these things of yours ?
Well , I think I can pump 20 cc
of strychnine nitrate into him .
If I can get close enough .
Get this little needle through his skin ?
No , I can 't do that .
But if I can get him close to this cage ,
I can get him in the mouth .
That shark 'll rip that cage to pieces .
You got any better suggestions ?
( Quint ) Easy . Easy .
All right .
Up she goes .
Ease her up .
Ain 't got no spit .
Try and keep him off me until I 'm lower .
Okay , okay , I 'm ready .
[ whirring ]
[ bubbling ]
Bring him up , God damn it .
Bring him up now !
Pull it up . Pull it .
Pull him up . Come on , Quint , bring him in .
It 's giving way !
Rig something ! Rig something !
Got it ?
It 's coming .
Slow it down .
Slower .
[ Quint screaming ]
[ panting ]
[ screaming ]
[ grunts ]
All right , come on .
Show me the tank . Show me the tank .
Blow up !
Smile , you son of a bitch !
[ gun fires ]
[ exclaiming ]
[ seagulls cawing ]
[ both chuckling ]
Quint ?
No .
Can we get in on those ?
( Brody ) Hey , what day is this ?
( Hooper ) It 's Wednesday . It 's Tuesday , I think .
[ both panting ]
I think the tide 's with us .
Keep kicking .
I used to hate the water .
[ laughs ]
I can 't imagine why .